<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PinGodGame on PinGod AddOns</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/</link><description>Recent content in PinGodGame on PinGod AddOns</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PinGodGame.tscn - Scene</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/pingodgame.tscn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/pingodgame.tscn/</guid><description>view full image
This scene is autoloaded with the game with all of its child scenes.
Selecting the scene will display the exports options in the scene inspector, see the highlighted right panel in the image.
These godot script exports are created in the PinGodGame.cs script as [Export] properties and the values set here will be saved into the parent scene file, in this case PinGodGame.tscn
Here we have enabled recording and playback file is set, saved to the scene.</description></item><item><title>MachineConfig (Items)</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/items/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/items/</guid><description>In the game/PinGodGame.tscn scenes inspector in Godot editor you can edit the machines Coils, Switches, Lamps, Leds.
This can be accessed from the MachineConfig scene by selecting it.
When the game is loaded these items will be added to the machine.
When adding from the UI (green box) select String and Int for the value.
It&amp;rsquo;s quicker to edit this scene file in a text editor and add your items directly in there with the name and number.</description></item><item><title>Ball Trough (Scene)</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/trough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/trough/</guid><description>The Trough.tscn handles the ball trough, ball saving, trough switches, early save switches, shooter lane switch.
Included in the examples PinGodGame.tscn tree.
Most cases you will leave the default settings here, but you can add more switches from this.
Trough / Ball Save Options Trough switche names Ball save seconds Ball save lamp name Ball save multiball seconds Early Ball Save switches Number of Balls to Save Trough Solenoid(coil) Plunger lane switch name Set what to do on ball started Ball search options Enabled Ball Search coils to pulse (usually saucers, scoops not the trough) Search stop switches = Switches that stop the search Search wait time = Time to wait before pulsing coils Trough Class Reference</description></item><item><title>AudioManager</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/audiomanager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/audiomanager/</guid><description>AudioManager Class Reference
Add global music, sfx, voice sounds.
See AudioManager</description></item><item><title>Overlays (Developing)</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/devoverlays/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/devoverlays/</guid><description>Scenes to overlay on screen like switches and light states
Lamp Overlay Enabled This enables the LampMatrix in the DevOverlays. Options are available on the LampMatrix to change coloumns and count. Customize in your own game if need more advanced.
Switch Overlay Enabled This enables the SwitchOverlay in the DevOverlays. Options are available on the SwitchOverlay to change coloumns.
Switches can be clicked on screen.</description></item><item><title>PinGodGame.cs - Script</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/pingodgame.cs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/pingodgame.cs/</guid><description>This script is autoloaded from the scene when the display window is launched and has many methods.
Modes and other scenes can get access to this from the root tree. GetNode&amp;lt;PinGodGame&amp;gt;(&amp;quot;/root/PinGodGame&amp;quot;).
Exports Scene inspector uses [export]s that are defined in game\PinGodGame.cs. You can add your own to your game from inheriting from the PinGodGame
Godot - Overrides _EnterTree = Gets user cmd line args, loads data and settings, creates trough, sets up ball search and audio manager</description></item><item><title>Recording / Playback</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/recordings-playback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/pingodgame/recordings-playback/</guid><description>Quick guide on how to record and playback a game. Recording a game can speed up your game development for game logic.
They would usually start off by using trough switches adding credits and starting a game, then any events after this to test any recorded sequence.
Recording Recording files are saved in the user://recordings/recordname.record
Example game dir: C:\Users\UserName\AppData\Roaming\Godot\app_userdata\BasicGameGodot\recordings
&amp;nbsp;Note You can get to the app_data directory for the game using app_data bat file</description></item></channel></rss>