<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on PinGod AddOns</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on PinGod AddOns</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Godot - Installation</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/installation/</guid><description>Download Godot editor Download the editor at https://godotengine.org/ Godot is portable (no installation required) (Version 3.4 C# MONO) It&amp;rsquo;s up to you where you extract the files to but for simplicity sake C:\Godot\</description></item><item><title>Godot - Environment Configuration</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/configuration/</guid><description>Set Environment path to Godot You should rename the Godot executable to godot and add to Environment paths on your system for access ease and scripts to use.
After you&amp;rsquo;ve done this you can run godot from the environment, command line.
This is helpful to load projects with the godot command and using the .bat files provided requires this name.
How to add to environment (Windows) Quick Way (Option 1) Open a cmd.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Git Clone</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-setup-git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-setup-git/</guid><description>Git Setup Use Git to pull the repositories from Github, you don&amp;rsquo;t need a Github account just the software to do this.
Git For Windows - Download Once the installer has started, follow the instructions as provided in the Git Setup wizard screen until the installation is complete. Open the windows command prompt (or Git Bash). Type git version to verify Git was installed.
Clone - Option 1 Create a directory on machine where you are developing named pingod, this could be anything but we need a directory to clone into.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Linking AddOns</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-setup-addons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-setup-addons/</guid><description>To run the BasicGameGodot project you will need the addons directory linked or copied.
These addons contain base files and pinball framework that a game will use.
Link the PinGod.VP.AddOns You can copy the addons directory to your project (BasicGameGodot in this example), but it&amp;rsquo;s better to use a symbolic link to the addons so we are not duplicating files and you can keep the same addons across projects.
Running the _link_addons.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Project.Godot</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-project/</guid><description>&amp;nbsp;Tip Use Alt+D in the project directory, type godot -e then enter to load project
&amp;nbsp;Tip You can use the .bat files in the projects root directory to load a project with . _godot_editor.bat
file what it does _link_addons.bat Links the pingod-addons repository addons directory into BasicGameGodot _godot_export_full.bat Exports Windows Desktop which is executable and main pack _godot_export_pck.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Godot Loaded</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-godot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-godot/</guid><description>PinGodAddOns.cs plugin disabled on first load This warning can be skipped.
This plugin addon is for adding some custom controls for the Godot UI. BlinkingLabel is one example.
Build The MainScene should be visible and you can build the project (top right button).
If build success, you can re-enable the plugin if you need to, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t needed to run the game for now.
Play Hit F5 to run the game.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Window</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-window/</guid><description>Window controls key action F1 Settings Menu F2 Toggle Window Border F8 Quit? Settings Audio Display Fullscreen FPS Game Some basic game settings PinGod Read/Write states can be disabled when not running with a simulator.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Game</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game/</guid><description>Game default controls Keys action 5 Credits Q,W,E,R Trough Switches 1-4 1 Start Game Simulating with keypress actions Add credits (5), hold all the trough switches down (QWER) then push start (1).
Add some points with Y = switch 22 inlane_l
Simulate ball drain by activating all the trough switches.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Visual Pinball</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-vp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-vp/</guid><description>Now that the game is building and running it can be launched with Visual Pinball.
Table can be run from any location in Visual Pinball.
The controller will load the game when the vp player is launched.
&amp;nbsp;Tip Use the _vp_edit.bat or _vp_play.bat to open the table easier
Provided you have the controller setup and have built the godot project this will play.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Visual Pinball Script</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-vp-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-vp-script/</guid><description>BasicGame-PinGod.vbs A script with the same name is included with the table. This will be used with the visual pinball script editor.
This can make it easier to edit outside of table, keep track of changes etc. At the top of this image it shows MODIFYING EXTERNAL.
PinGod.VP.Controller The first section marked in red is the PinGod.VP.Controller initialization.
Game Project Location When debugging, if the games Godot project is relative to the table (the same as this repo), then you won&amp;rsquo;t have to adjust the script for the GameDirectory.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Exporting</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-exporting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-exporting/</guid><description>You can export the game to be used without the Godot editor. The Build folder will be used to export to.
Godot Export file does? _godot_export_full.bat Exports Windows Desktop which is executable and main pack _godot_export_pck.bat Exports Windows Desktop Pack which updates the main pack. The executable will be the same for all games as it basically is Godot You only need to run _godot_export_full.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Assets and Packs</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-assets-and-packs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-assets-and-packs/</guid><description>The BasicGamePck directory is an extra exporter for asset packs, doing it this way means we can keep assets from the game packs separated. One example is that if the assets never change then you don&amp;rsquo;t need to update those files. You may also want to make a base asset pack to copy and load across multiple games. You are not limited to media, it could be a scene with assets included.</description></item><item><title>BasicGame - Resources from packs</title><link>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://FlippingFlips.github.io/pingod-addons/getting-started/basicgame-game-resources/</guid><description>In the PinGodGame.tscn is a ResourcePreloader node. When this is loaded with the scene it looks for the packs you have set in the Resource Packs.
This scene was duplicated from addons\PinGodGame\Scenes\Resources.tscn and uses the resource script in addons.
We need to have this copy in our project otherwise if using the addons it will change it for all games.
Resource Packs By default the collection includes the export packs in the previous section.</description></item></channel></rss>